Register of the Stanislaw Mikolajczyk Papers, 1899-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
Stanislaw Mikolajczyk Papers,
1899-1966
78111
Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw, 1901-1966
207 manuscript boxes, 9 oversize boxes (92 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, notes, newsletters, clippings, photographs, tape recordings, motion picture film, and printed matter, relating to communism in Eastern Europe and Poland, agriculture in Poland, Polish politics, especially during World War II, Polish-Soviet relations, the International Peasant Union, the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe, and Polish emigre politics.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (233 reels).
Digital copy in Poland's National Digital Archive at http://szukajwarchiwach.pl/800/22/0/-/. It was digitized from microfilm by the Polish State Archives.
Access Points
International Peasant Union.; Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe (1945-1949); Agriculture--Poland.; Anti-communist movements--United States.; Communism.; Poles--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; Europe, Eastern.; Poland.; Poland--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; Poland--History--Occupation, 1939-1945.; Poland--Politics and government.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--Foreign relations--Poland.; United States.; Statesmen--Poland.
Biographical Note
1901 July 18 Born, Holsterhausen, Westphalia, Germany
1918 Member and active participant of Sokoly, Polish insurrection against the Germans
1920 Private, Polish Army, Polish-Russo War Graduated from Agricultural High School, People's University
1924 Secretary, Polish Peasant Party, Poznan district Editor, Wloscianin Wielkopolski
1930-1935 Parliament member, Polish Peasant Party
1935 Chairman, Poznan Association of Agricultural Circles
1937 Leader, peasant strikes
1939 Private, September campaign Interned in Hungary; escaped to France Vice-President, Polish Parliament in exile
1939-1941 Acting President, Polish National Council
1941-1942 Minister of Interior
1941-1943 Deputy Prime Minister, Sikorski government
1943 July-1944 November Prime Minister
1944 Went to Moscow and Washington
1945 Deputy Prime Minister, Warsaw, Provisional Polish Government of National Unity Minister of Agriculture President, Polish Peasant Party
1947 June Resigned from government posts Leader of parliamentary opposition
1947 October 20 Left Poland
1947 November 26 Arrived in New York
1948 Founder, Polish Peasant Party in exile
1948-1964 President, International Peasant Union
1950 President, Polish National Democratic Committee
1950-1966 President, Assembly of Captive European Nations
1951 Member, Central and Eastern European Committee
1955 Went to Japan
1956 Presided over International Peasant Union Congress, Paris
1966 December 13 Died
Scope and Content
The Stanislaw Mikolajczyk papers were acquired in 1979 from his son Marian. Shortly thereafter, the late Helena Sworakowska prepared a preliminary inventory, which remained in use for nearly two decades. Detailed processing and preservation microfilming have now been made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Taube Family Foundation. In addition, the grant provides depositing a microfilm copy of these materials in the State Archives of Poland in Warsaw.
The papers cover mostly the second part of Mikolajczyk's life, beginning in 1939 when, as a soldier, he made his way to France to join the Polish government-in-exile (which later established itself in London). He served successively as vice-president of the Polish parliament, president of the Polish National Council, minister of the interior, deputy prime minister, and prime minister after the death of Wladyslaw Sikorski in 1943. (As a close associate of the general throughout those years and his successor, Mikolajczyk's archives contain part of Sikorski's working files.)
The government service series covers Mikolajczyk's activities in those capacities, as well as his interactions with other offices of the Polish government-in-exile. Particularly significant are the papers relating to his tenure as prime minister, as they reflect a dramatic period of Poland's wartime history; that is especially evident in light of numerous intelligence reports.
While the London years are well documented, the period from 1945 to 1947, during which Mikolajczyk served in the provisional governement in Warsaw, is not. Indeed, when he left Poland in October of 1947, forced once again into exile, Mikolajczyk took with him only a small dossier of materials on political persecussions. Complementing the secret police records surviving in Poland, this part of the collection (found in the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe series) fills important gaps in the country's history after 1945.
After 1948, like many other of the Central and East European exiles, Mikolajczyk was very active in unifying émigré circles from Poland as well as from other East European countries. He remained a prominent émigré figure until his death in 1966, and was the leading personality, representing the entire region, in the stuggle against Soviet plans to communize Eastern and Central Europe. His closeness to political circles in Washington allowed him to form the first East European lobby and to put the issue of Soviet occupation on the political agenda of consecutive United States administrations.
Mikolajczyk founded and/or presided over many organizations such as the Assembly of Captive European Nations, the International Peasant Union, the Polish Peasant Party in exile, and the Polish National Democratic Committee. He was also very active on behalf of Radio Free Europe. All those efforts are widely represented in the collection, with each of the major organizations he was involved in constituting a separate series.
An avid collector of documents, Mikolajczyk was very aware of their significance for history. He also amassed clippings from numerous sources, now gathered into a printed matter series.
Finally, researchers will find an extensive audio-visual series containing a very large number of photographs and of audio tapes.
Zbigniew Stanczyk
August 1999
Series Description
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1939-1966., Boxes 1-8
  Appointment books, articles, biographies, clippings, communiqués, correspondence, identification papers, transcripts, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1943-1965., Boxes 8-13
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
- DIARIES, 1944-1950., Box 13
  Handwritten and typewritten diaries arranged chronologically.
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1941-1965., Boxes 14-24
  Interviews, speeches, statements, and writings, arranged alphabetically by category and therein chronologically. Includes related correspondence, clippings, book reviews, and miscellany.
- GOVERNMENT SERVICE FILE, 1940-1946., Boxes 25-64
  Appeals, communiqués, correspondence, dispatches, instructions, lists, log books, maps, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, reports, speeches, statements, transcripts of talks, clippings and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by name of office (in Polish) in which Mikolajczyk served or with which he interacted. Translations of office names are given in parentheses, and positions he held are given in brackets.
- RADIO FREE EUROPE FILE, 1949-1965., Boxes 65-74
  Brochures, commentaries, correspondence, interviews, memoranda, newsletters, reports, speeches, transcripts, clippings and other printed matter, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
- POLSKI KOMITET NARODOWO DEMOKRATYCZNY FILE (POLISH NATIONAL DEMOCRATIC COMMITTEE), 1950-1963., Boxes 74-79
  Brochures, correspondence, declarations, essays, itineraries, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletters, notes, reports, speeches, clippings and other printed matter, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
- POROZUMIENIE STRONNICTW DEMOKRATYCZNYCH, TYMCZASOWA RADA JEDNOSCI NARODOWEJ FILE (DEMOCRATIC ALLIANCE, PROVISIONAL COUNCIL OF NATIONAL UNITY), 1927-1956., Boxes 80-82
  Bulletins, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, resolutions, speeches, transcripts of sessions, clippings and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- POLSKA RADA POLITYCZNA FILE (POLISH POLITICAL COUNCIL), 1948-1953., Box 82
  Correspondence, publications, session transcripts, statute, and clippings, arranged chronologically.
- POLSKIE STRONNICTWO LUDOWE FILE (POLISH PEASANT PARTY), 1899-1966., Boxes 83-106
  Brochures, bulletins, circulars, correspondence, essays, itineraries, memoranda, minutes, newsletters, notes, programs, reports, resolutions, speeches, clippings and other printed matter, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- POLSKA PARTIA SOCJALISTYCZNA FILE (POLISH SOCIALIST PARTY), 1940-1963., Boxes 106-107
  Correspondence, programs, transcripts of talks, clippings and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- ASSEMBLY OF CAPTIVE EUROPEAN NATIONS FILE, 1950-1966., Boxes 108-117
  Addresses, brochures, bulletins, clippings, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, newsletters, notes, publications, reports, resolutions, and speeches, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- INTERNATIONAL PEASANT UNION FILE, 1948-1966., Boxes 118-146
  Articles, brochures, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, newsletters, notes, press releases, programs, reports, resolutions, speeches, and statements, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1966., Boxes 147-166
  Brochures, bulletins, correspondence, essays, memoranda, newsletters, notes, reports, speeches, clippings and other printed matter, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- PRINTED MATTER, 1941-1965., Boxes 167-202
  Clippings arranged alphabetically by country and therein chronologically or by title of newspaper.
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1936-1966., Boxes 203-215
  Still and motion picture film, phonorecords, phonotape cassette, phonotapes, photographs, and photo albums, arranged alphabetically by genre.
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1947., Box 216
  Carbon matrix of Stanislaw Mikolajczyk's speech at the Polish Parliament, 1947 June 23.
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1939-1966
  - General
    - Appointment books
      - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1941 (Folder 2)
      - 1942 (Folder 3)
      - 1943 (Folder 4)
      - 1944 (Folder 5)
      - 1945 (Folder 6)
      - 1946 (Folder 7)
      - 1947 (Folder 8)
      - 1948 (Folder 9)
      - 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1950 (Folder 2)
      - 1951 (Folder 3)
      - 1953 (Folder 4)
      - 1954 (Folder 5)
      - 1955 (Folder 6)
      - 1956 (Folder 7)
      - 1957 (Folder 8)
      - 1958 (Folder 9)
      - 1959 (Folder 10)
      - 1960 (Folder 11)
      - 1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 1962 (Folder 2)
      - 1963 (Folder 3)
      - 1964 (Folder 4)
      - 1965 (Folder 5)
      - 1966 (Folder 6)
    - Biographical sketches (Folder 7)
    - Business cards (Folder 8)
    - Contracts for book signing, Paris, 1952 (Folder 9)
    - Identification papers
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Affidavits and passports
        - American, 1952-1963 (Folder 11)
        - French, 1940 (Folder 12)
        - Polish, 1940 (Folder 13)
      - Visas, 1955-1957 (Folder 14)
    - Printed matter regarding Mikolajczyk (Folder 15)
  - Escape from Poland, 1947
    - Communiqués
      - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Radio Warsaw (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence of Jan Ciechanowski, 1947 November 10, related to Mikolajczyk's escape (Folder 3)
    - Diary, London, November 3-25 (Folder 4)
    - Letters of congratulations sent to Mrs. Mikolajczyk, 1947 October-November (Folder 5)
    - Press clippings
      - American, 1947
        - January-September (Folder 6)
        - October (Folder 7)
        - November (Folder 8)
      - Belgian, 1947 (Folder 9)
      - British
        - 1947
          - October (Folder 10)
          - November (Folder 11)
        - 1948 (Folder 12)
      - French, 1947 (Folder 13)
      - Italian, 1947 (Folder 14)
      - Polish
        - Communist and peasant in Poland
          - 1947
            - August (Folder 15)
            - October-November (Folder 16)
          - 1948 (Folder 17)
        - Émigré, 1947
          - American (Folder 18)
          - Austrian (Folder 19)
          - British (Folder 20)
          - French (Box 5, Folder 1)
          - Swedish (Folder 2)
      - Swedish, 1947 (Folder 3)
      - Swiss, 1947 (Folder 4)
    - Subject file
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Fellow escapees (Folder 6)
      - New York reception (Folder 7)
    - Transcript of conversation between two unidentified individuals (J. R. and W. U.), 1947, relating to Mikolajczyk's escape (Folder 8)
  - Trial, 1952. See also SUBJECT FILE/Anders, Wladyslaw
    - Press clippings
      - French (Folder 9)
      - Polish
        - Communist (Folder 10)
        - Émigré (Folder 11)
    - Transcripts of proceedings (Folder 12)
  - Trips
    - Europe
      - 1948 June 22-August 14
        - Itinerary (Folder 13)
        - Materials relating to visit in the Vatican city, July 12
          - Clippings (Folder 14)
          - Notes (Folder 15)
          - Reports (Folder 16)
      - 1949 June 30-October 6
        - General
          - July (Folder 17)
          - August (Folder 18)
          - September
            - 1-15 (Folder 19)
            - 16-22 (Folder 20)
        - Itinerary (Folder 21)
      - 1952 January-March (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - 1953
        - Correspondence (Folder 2)
        - Speeches (Folder 3)
        - Talks (Folder 4)
      - 1956
        - April-June (Folder 5)
        - October-November (Folder 6)
      - 1958 July-November
        - Itinerary (Folder 7)
        - Reports (Folder 8)
      - 1962
        - Clippings (Folder 9)
        - Timetable (Folder 10)
    - Japan, 1955 October-December
      - Book with signatures of people Mikolajczyk met during his trip (Folder 11)
      - Correspondence (Folder 12)
      - Itinerary (Folder 13)
      - Materials in Japanese (Folder 14)
      - Personal notes
        - Part 1 (Folder 15)
        - Part 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Press file
        - English (Folder 2)
        - Japanese (Folder 3)
        - Polish (Folder 4)
      - Reports
        - In Polish (typescript). Includes some text in English (Folder 5)
        - In English, put out by the International Peasant Union (mimeographed and printed). Includes a cover letter to John Foster Dulles, 1956 March 1 (Folder 6)
      - Speeches
        - General (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Drafts (Folder 2)
  - Death, 1966 December 13
    - Press file
      - American
        - International Peasant Union Bulletin (Folder 3)
        - New York Times (Folder 4)
        - Washington Post (Folder 5)
      - Czech-American
        - Katolik (Folder 6)
        - Narod (Folder 7)
      - French - Le Monde (Folder 8)
      - Polish
        - Communist - Krajowa Agencja Informacyjna (Folder 9)
        - Émigré
          - Canada
            - Czas (Folder 10)
            - Zwiazkowiec (Folder 11)
          - France - Narodowiec (Folder 12)
          - Germany - Ostatnie Wiadomosci (Folder 13)
          - Great Britain
            - Dziennik Polski (Folder 14)
            - Gazeta Niedzielna (Folder 15)
            - Jutro Polski (Folder 16)
            - Orzel Bialy (Folder 17)
            - Robotnik (Folder 18)
            - Wiadomosci (Folder 19)
          - United States
            - Ameryka-Echo (Folder 20)
            - Dziennik Chicagowski (Folder 21)
            - Dziennik Polski (Folder 22)
            - Dziennik Zwiazkowy (Folder 23)
            - Gazeta Polonii (Folder 24)
            - Glos Ludowy (Folder 25)
            - Gwiazda Polarna (Folder 26)
            - Nowy Swiat (Folder 27)
            - Polish American Journal (Folder 28)
            - Robotnik Polski (Folder 29)
            - Sokol Polski (Folder 30)
      - Swiss - Neue Zürcher Zeitung (Folder 31)
    - Radio program transcripts
      - B.B.C. (Folder 32)
      - Radio Free Europe (Folder 33)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1943-1965
  - General
    - 1945
      - January (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - February (Folder 35)
      - March (Folder 36)
      - April (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - May (Folder 2)
      - June
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Departure for Poland (Folder 4)
    - 1947
      - September (Folder 5)
      - October (Folder 6)
      - November
        - Letters
          - English
            - General (Folder 7)
            - Government officials (Folder 8)
          - Polish (Folder 9)
        - Telegrams (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - December (Folder 2)
    - 1948
      - General
        - January (Folder 3)
        - February
          - 1-15 (Folder 4)
          - 16-27 (Folder 5)
        - March (Folder 6)
        - April (Folder 7)
        - May (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - June (Folder 2)
        - July (Folder 3)
        - August (Folder 4)
        - September (Folder 5)
        - October (Folder 6)
        - November (Folder 7)
        - December (Folder 8)
      - Speaking engagements
        - January (Folder 9)
        - February (Folder 10)
        - March (Folder 11)
        - April (Folder 12)
        - May-December (Folder 13)
    - 1949
      - January-March (Folder 14)
      - April (Folder 15)
      - May (Folder 16)
      - June (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - July-September (Folder 2)
      - October-December (Folder 3)
    - 1954
      - January-March (Folder 4)
      - April-June (Folder 5)
      - July-September (Folder 6)
      - October-December (Folder 7)
  - Auriol, Vincent, 1949 (Folder 8)
  - Biddle, Anthony, 1943 (Folder 9)
  - Churchill, Winston, 1945-1947 (Folder 10)
  - Clark, Archibald, 1945 (Folder 11)
  - Dulles, John F., 1954 (Folder 12)
  - Eden, Anthony, 1944-1945, 1956 (Folder 13)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1953-1954 (Folder 14)
  - Emmet, Christopher (Common Cause). Includes an appeal to the Italian people, 1948 April 16 (Folder 15)
  - Florczyk, Leszek, 1955 (Folder 16)
  - Gabryelski, Jerzy
    - 1955-1961 (Folder 17)
    - 1964 (Folder 18)
  - Gross, Feliks, 1954 (Folder 19)
  - Hoover, Allan, 1964 (Folder 20)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1947-1949 (Folder 21)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1965 (Folder 22)
  - Karski, Jan, 1944-1945 (Folder 23)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1960 (Folder 24)
  - Klein, Julius, 1951 (Folder 25)
  - Korszynski, Franciszek, 1959 (Folder 26)
  - Kot, Stanislaw
    - 1944 (Folder 27)
    - 1948 (Folder 28)
    - 1949 (Folder 29)
    - 1950 (Folder 30)
    - 1951 (Folder 31)
    - 1952 (Folder 32)
    - 1953 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1954-1962 (Folder 2)
  - Lane, Arthur B., 1955 (Folder 3)
  - Modelska, Stanislawa, 1963. Includes correspondence of Paul Tadeus and Franciszek Wilk, particularly regarding the monthly Orka (Folder 4)
  - Murphy, Robert, 1959 (Folder 5)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1959 (Folder 6)
  - Paderewski, Ignacy, 1940-1941 (Folder 7)
  - Paul VI, Pope, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Polish-Canadian organizations, 1947-1950 (Folder 9)
  - Raczkiewicz, Wladyslaw, 1939-1944 (Folder 10)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1944 (Folder 11)
  - Schoenfeld, Rudolf, 1944-1945 (Folder 12)
  - Sikorska, Helena, 1963 (Folder 13)
  - Sikorski, Wladyslaw, 1941-1943 (Folder 14)
  - Soroka, Waclaw, 1962 (Folder 15)
  - Truman, Harry, 1951 (Folder 16)
- DIARIES, 1944-1950.
  Years 1948-1949 include clippings covering the period. See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Escape from Poland; GOVERNMENT SERVICE FILE/General/Premier/Moscow trips/Mikolajczyk/Fourth trip
  - 1944 December 13-1945 June 6 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - 1948
    - March-August (Folder 18)
    - August-December (Folder 19)
  - 1949
    - January-May (Folder 20)
    - May-December (Folder 21)
  - 1950 February-September (Folder 22)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1941-1965
  - Interviews
    - 1941 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1945 (Folder 2)
    - 1947 (Folder 3)
    - 1948 (Folder 4)
    - 1950 (Folder 5)
    - 1952 (Folder 6)
    - 1954 (Folder 7)
    - 1956 (Folder 8)
    - 1959 (Folder 9)
    - 1962 (Folder 10)
  - Speeches
    - 1941-1943
      - List (Folder 11)
      - Nos. 1-10 (Folder 12)
      - Nos. 11-14 (Folder 13)
    - 1944 December 14, "Conditions of a Russian-Polish Settlement," London (Folder 14)
    - 1945 May 21, account of Mikolajczyk's speech on the 50th anniversary of the founding of the Polish Peasant Party (Folder 15)
    - 1945-1947. "Mowy prezesa Stanislawa Mikolajczyka od dnia powrotu do kraju" (folder title given by Mikolajczyk)
      - List (Folder 16)
      - Nos. 1-19 (Folder 17)
      - Nos. 20-35 (Folder 18)
      - Nos. 36-44 (Folder 19)
      - Nos. 45-54 (Folder 20)
      - Nos. 55-70 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1947
      - General - Itinerary (Folder 2)
      - May - Peasant party's political line (Folder 3)
      - November
        - General (Folder 4)
        - Great Britain. House of Commons, November 18 (in English and Polish) (Folder 5)
      - December
        - General (Folder 6)
        - "From Yalta to Cominform" (in English and Polish) (Folder 7)
    - 1948
      - General
        - General
          - Itinerary (Folder 8)
          - Notes (Folder 9)
          - Typescripts
            - Part 1 (Folder 10)
            - Part 2 (Folder 11)
            - Part 3 (Folder 12)
        - January
          - Part 1 (Box 16, Folder 1)
          - Part 2 (Folder 2)
      - Countries visited by Mikolajczyk
        - Belgium (Folder 3)
        - United States - Chicago (Folder 4)
      - Poland's internal situation (Folder 5)
    - 1949
      - General
        - General (Folder 6)
        - Itinerary (Folder 7)
      - Congressional Record (Folder 8)
      - "Teczka polityczna od stycznia 1949: Wywiady i przemowienia" (folder title given by Mikolajczyk) (Folder 9)
      - "Teczka Przemowien i Oswiadczen" (folder title given by Mikolajczyk)
        - List (Folder 10)
        - No. 1 (Folder 11)
        - Nos. 2-6 (Folder 12)
        - Nos. 7-11 (Folder 13)
        - No. 12 (Folder 14)
        - Nos. 13-18 (Folder 15)
        - Nos. 19-28 (Folder 16)
        - No. 29 (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - No. 32 (Folder 2)
    - 1950
      - General
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Itinerary (Folder 4)
      - January (Folder 5)
      - February (Folder 6)
      - April (Folder 7)
      - May (Folder 8)
      - June (Folder 9)
      - July-September (Folder 10)
      - October (Folder 11)
      - November (Folder 12)
      - December
        - General (Folder 13)
        - 2 (Folder 14)
        - 5 (Folder 15)
        - 14 (Folder 16)
    - 1951
      - General
        - General (Folder 17)
        - Itinerary (Folder 18)
    - 1952
      - General - Itinerary (Folder 19)
      - January-June (Folder 20)
      - July-December (Folder 21)
    - 1953
      - General - Itinerary (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - January
        - General (Folder 2)
        - "Accelerated Sovietization and Intensified Communist Terror Characterize Recent Developments in Poland" (Folder 3)
        - "Last Bolshevik Congress and the Agrarian Problems behind the Iron Curtain" (Folder 4)
        - "The Real Causes of the Breakdown of the Soviet Agricultural Production" (Folder 5)
      - March
        - "Eastern Europe and the Policy of Liberation" (Folder 6)
        - "Prospects for Poland" (Folder 7)
        - Untitled lecture on Central Europe before the Polish Federalist Association (Folder 8)
      - April - Twentieth century crisis of Poland (Folder 9)
      - May (Folder 10)
      - July